CHRIS MENDES Contract Front-end Web Developer

Croydon, South London ADDRESS: DATE OF BIRTH: 1985 (Age 29)

inbox@chrismendes.co.uk NATIONALITY: EMAIL: **British**

PORTFOLIO: chrismendes.london LOOKING FOR: **Contract roles only**

INTRODUCTION

I'm an experienced Web Developer, primarily with front-end development, with eight years commercial experience working on a wide range of projects. With a natural flair for problem-solving I am a very determined, resourceful, and professional individual driven to create commercially successful products to high technical standards.

My website – chrismendes.london – has a thorough service description, a complete overview of technical skills and expertise, full work portfolio, code samples, and other useful information. I invite you to visit.

SKILLSET

KEY SKILLS:

- HTML5, CSS3, Sass/LESS, Twitter Bootstrap/Foundation
- JavaScript, jQuery, Backbone.js, Underscore, Require.js
- PHP, MySQL, Laravel, Codelgniter
- Git, Grunt, Bower

KEY KNOWLEDGE:

- Building web applications from scratch
- Object-oriented, modular, scalable code
- Responsive web development
- Web performance and optimisation

EMPLOYMENT

May 2014 – Oct 2014 Capablue

Waterloo, London (3 month+ contract)

Contract Front-end Web Developer

At this highly innovative company - owned by Arqiva, a leading communications infrastructure company - I was drafted in to develop a white-label product for a new multi-channel live TV streaming web application accessible on desktops, tablets, and mobile devices (similar concept to BBC iPlayer).

After the success of this project, I was subsequently asked to build from scratch a completely new version of Capablue's own company website. Working with a freelance Designer, a Junior Developer, QA Testers, Project Manager, and Marketing Manager, I led the development and together we successfully delivered the new website.

Mar 2012 - May 2014

DNX Marketing Guildford, Surrey Web Developer

Working at this multi award winning agency (B2B Agency of the Year 2012 and 2013), my job was to collaborate with project teams that consist of account managers, designers, copywriters, and project managers, and build the agreed creative solution within the set time-frame and budget.

This predominantly involved building responsive websites with varying and wide-ranging client-side and server-side requirements, but also although less often, HTML emails, animated banners, and games.

Key responsibilities:

- Coding the responsive front-end of new websites with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript/jQuery, and the Twitter Bootstrap framework
- Coding the back-end of new websites with PHP, MySQL, using the Codelgniter MVC framework
- Meeting with account managers and project managers to be briefed on new projects, and liaising with designers and other developers to propose, discuss, and agree on the envisaged end product and its technical makeup
- Supporting other developers with technical input and general guidance
- Running team meetings once every week, submitting meeting agendas, facilitating discussion and agreement, recording and sharing minutes, pursuing action – a responsibility delegated to me by the department manager

Mar 2010 – Mar 2012 <u>Fingo Marketing</u>

Web Developer

Epsom, Surrey

My role at this marketing agency primarily was to build new websites based on the visual designs produced by the creative team. As the leading developer I worked to one extent or another on the majority of all projects collaborating closely with the company directors, web designers, and the project manager from kick-off to completion.

- Creating fresh new websites ranging from static brochure sites, to CMS driven sites and more bespoke sites
- Providing technical input to support project requirements gathering and internal processes
- Liaising with clients in relation to ongoing maintenance for previously developed websites

Sep 2006 – Jun 2008

Music Talents Ltd. Enfield, Middlesex

Web Developer

I was responsible for developing, maintaining, and advancing the company's efforts to sell its products on the Internet via its various ecommerce websites. This involved working with a range of technologies such as HTML, CSS, ASP, PHP, MySQL, MS SQL, and WordPress.

- Expanding main ecommerce website developing new functionality and implementing change as described by the business manager and company director
- Supporting development towards new websites selling the company products

Mar 2005 - Sep 2006

Sounds Musical Ltd.

Waltham Abbey, Essex

Junior Web Developer

Within the IT department of this ecommerce company, my job was to conduct wide-ranging maintenance and testing on the company's ecommerce website.

- Implementing front-end additions/amends for the main ecommerce website (HTML, CSS, ASP)
- Working through reported issues/errors/bugs with the site fix, test and confirm as resolved

EDUCATION

2008 – 2010 <u>King's College London</u>

PgD Advanced Software Engineering

Strand, London

Topics included:

Software Engineering for the Internet, Software Architecture & Design, The Internet Infrastructure Software, Measurement & Testing, Distributed Computing, Access Control Strategy, Artificial Intelligence.

2004 - 2008

London Metropolitan University

BSc (Hons) Computer Visualisation & Games (2:1)

Islington, London

Topics included:

Fundamentals of Computer Science, Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structures & Algorithms, Database Systems, Software Usability, 2D Computer Graphics, 3D Animation, Game Applications.

PERSONAL INTERESTS

- Learning new tools and web technologies such as AngularJS and CoffeeScript
- Playing football every weekend for a Saturday league team, and during the week for a 5-a-side team
- Keeping fit via fitness classes and circuit exercises at home
- TV dramas with rich storytelling like Game of Thrones and Breaking Bad!
- British Army. Former army reservist in the TA for six years